Yeah.
My grandfather was a journalist.
My mom.
She was just a little girl when it
happened.
An adventurer. my mom called him.
Anything or anywhere for a story.
Something was wrong in those caves.
I have to go exploring down there.
His disappearance affected her every
single day.
I know she went there. looking for
answers.
Now all I have left of them both is this
old journal.
But it's a start.
I called everyone.
What do you mean. everyone?
Ethan. Nick.
Ethan?
He's in the TA and...
What are the police doing?
We can go down there ourselves.
We can try and find her.
I can't ask them to do it.
How are you holding up?
Whoa. check out that view.
Better hope we've brought enough
food and stuff.
I haven't seen a shot for miles.
Wow.
Cataloged everything from my side. so
from a scientific perspective at least.
we're covered.
Of course they have.
Hey. no way. is that... Holy shit. It's
her. It's Bitch Hiker.
For real.
Who? Ashley Winters.
The travel vlogger. She goes all over
the country doing all sorts of cool
Sorry. Bitch Hiker. She has like a
million followers.
Ethan. stop. This isn't a joyride.
I am. She's been a good Samaritan. Her
videos are insane.
We're here for Olivia's mum.
I really don't think this is a good
idea.
Anyway. she might know the area.
We don't have enough space in here.
Sure we do. She can always share with
me.
And the bitch hiker strikes again. Never
underestimate the power of the thumb.
people. Two thumbs. Sawyer.
Nick.
Ashley Winters. right? The bitch hiker.
The one and only. Are you guys fans of
the channel?
Huge fans.
So. where are you headed?
I'm actually looking for a haunted
castle in Scotland. I'm hoping to spend
night alone with some ghosties.
What are you guys doing in the middle of
nowhere?
Oh. we're going to explore some local
caves.
There's this legend about the. uh.
something called the Bone Keeper.
Are you serious?
Like a monster hunt or something?
Um. well. it's more just a legend.
really.
You know. like a myth.
We're heading to some cabins a few miles
up if you fancy jumping in the back.
Are you serious?
Are you seriously inviting a stranger on
our trip?
Yep.
Same old Ethan.
All right. fans. we might have had a
change of plans. I think we found
more exciting than ghosts. Guys. right.
this is supposed to be a serious
expedition. yeah?
Agreed. I vote no.
What's the deal with this bone keeper?
Oh. I'm just going to record everything.
Is that okay with everyone?
I film everything.
Absolutely. More cameras the better. I
say.
Great.
Perfect.
Okay. Bitch Hiker fans. meet my new
friend.
We are on the hunt for this mythical
bone keeper.
Sounds terrifying. right?
What is it?
It's a local myth about a creature in a
cave that collects human bones.
Well. there's more to it than that.
Oh. no. this is perfect.
It's exactly the kind of content that my
fans like.
It's not just a myth.
Olivia's mum went missing looking for
it.
At least we think so.
Oh. I'm so sorry. I had no idea.
Sorry. I didn't know.
If you want me to back off. I completely
understand.
No way. Look. your vlogging could really
help. More attention means more eyes on
the search. right?
Yeah.
Yeah. that's true. Well. I have a decent
amount of followers of...
We can help you find your mum in any
way. My channel's all yours.
What do you get out of it?
Well. content. obviously. but I can help
with expenses too. like travel. food.
anything. And I've got a portable
sleeping mat. so I won't even take up
See? She's practically paying her way
already.
I guess this just got a little bit more
interesting.
A whole lot less scientific.
It's like a nature.
Oh! It's absolutely stunning.
And check out all the equipment these
guys have prepared for some serious
campaign.
I hear this place is rich in some pretty
rare mineral deposits.
If you go deep enough.
Just waiting to be discovered by human
hands.
My posh bath and all.
Yours is one with the outdoor shower.
mate. Just like the way you grew up.
Oh. fuck you.
Bitchhiker Nation. welcome to the base
camp for our Bonekeeper expedition.
I know I was supposed to be exploring
Scottish castles that were haunted this
week. but when adventure calls for
something this juicy...
Now check out this place.
Total horror movie vibes. right? But in
a cozy way.
These views are the dive wall.
Hopefully not literally.
Kidding.
Now the real story is Olivia.
Her mother went missing in this cave and
monster or no monster. something
happened to her and we are going to find
answers.
Lovely. What is it?
It's my mum.
She used to sing it to me when I was a
baby.
She used to call me.
And I recorded it for me the next day.
It's
been a lifesaver at
times.
My dad used to play ABBA to get me to
sleep.
Which one do you fancy then?
Do you reckon they'll be out for it?
Mate. it's pretty obvious how it's going
to go down. We're going to the caves.
Ravi's going to be creaming over the
stalactites or whatever.
The girls are going to be cold and
tired. It's dark. so we'll keep close to
them. Make them feel safe. right?
There's no creatures. none of that
bullshit down there.
They'll see some bats and freak out.
We'll be in like Flynn.
Flynn?
Errol Flynn.
Who?
The black and white actor that used to
shag all the women.
Don't you know anything?
Are we interrupting something?
Nothing much.
Sorting out some gear.
Yeah. helmets. lights. torches. snacks.
emergency blanket.
Emergency blanket?
Well. yeah. Really? Better to have it
and not need it than need it and not
it.
You want to see what's in the other
pack?
Look.
it's getting dark.
We should probably start looking for
Harrison.
There's a local pub you've seen at a few
times. so it might be a good place to
start. I could go for a pint.
Yeah. good idea.
What can I do you for?
Three pints of whatever's local. a red.
a white and three packets of crisps.
please. Come from far?
All over the place.
What brings you here?
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
Try me.
I've seen it all and heard it all.
Two days ago. someone took a piss right
there where you stood.
Cleaned it all too.
Nice. So don't be shy.
Let it all out.
This place is like a confessional.
All right.
We're looking for someone. actually.
Someone that knows about certain cave
systems around here.
He goes by the name of Professor
Harrison.
We heard this was his local and thought
we'd have a little chat with him.
About what exactly?
Our friend's mum's been missing.
And. uh...
We think she might come to the caves.
Then why would she do something stupid
like that?
This gentleman's bothering you. Linda.
Do you need us to operate the door
policy for you?
I'm ready for that.
What about you. lad?
Guys. look. we're just going to have one
drink and then we're going to be on our
way. OK?
Is it just one drink. Linda?
Sure.
They seem like nice people.
Be a shame to see them get hurt.
So.
Stay away from the caves and keep your
bones where they belong.
Bones. eh?
So you believe in all that stuff?
And what stuff would that be?
The Bone Keeper.
That's what the papers called it. isn't
it?
The thing that's lurking in those caves.
The Bone Keeper.
I quite like the name myself. What about
you. Nick?
I mean. it sounds better than Bigfoot.
right? That just sounds like a Bigfoot.
Or Nessie. Loch Ness.
Wasn't that just a trick by the locals
to get the tourists to buy more
sandwiches?
Do you even sell sandwiches here?
You think you know something about
what's in those caves?
No?
Well. we're going to find out.
Joe. your pint.
It's going to be your last one.
Raskin.
So you believe in light. do you?
Creatures and stuff.
I believe.
Unless you want to get burnt. stay away
from the fire.
You get me?
Maybe putting out the fire is a better
option.
How are you going to do that?
We're going to find it fast.
You know this fella?
Yeah.
I know him.
But he's not going to tell you nothing.
Ruskin. was it?
Um. I'm Annabelle. This is Olivia.
Her mum went missing about two weeks
ago. We think Professor Harrison might
able to help. Please. Okay. we've come a
long way. and I can't go back without
trying.
If you could just tell us where we can
find him.
All right.
But you'd better time for me to get his
ass back down here. because we're not
selling enough whiskey.
He'd be hiding away.
Okay.
You sure you don't mind if I turn him up
at this time of night?
Give him a chance.
Yeah. I mean. he might be in the loo or
something.
Oh. he's dead already.
Whoa. Whoa.
Whatever you want.
I'm not in the mood.
So go away while you've still got faces.
Do you see any balaclavas here? What I
see is a gang of rural thieves.
Intending to threaten me.
Please. we just want to talk. I don't.
Look. listen. we know about the cave.
Can you just talk to us. please?
Please. Look. please.
Well. that went well.
Sorry. Liv.
Well. I'm going to go down there anyway.
so...
Professor Harrison?
I'm Olivia Wheeler.
You wrote about my grandfather. David
Wheeler.
He went missing in the cave.
I know who you are.
Look. whoever you are. whatever your
reasons. you must not go into those
Everyone who has gone in there has
remained in there. They have never come
alive.
And what do you think that is?
Well. millions of years of water pouring
through limestone creates
caves and perhaps...
concealed things that we know nothing
about.
But you know something. don't you?
Well. I may have some theories. but
that's all they are. just simple
They'll never be proved. When you'd like
to know for sure. we'll be going down
there with our phones. our cameras. all
with razor -sharp 4K.
If there's something down there. you'll
be able to see it all.
We just need to know which cave is. you
know.
The one.
Razor sharp 4K.
Do you know where those images will be?
They will be in the cameras.
And where will the cameras be? They will
be down there.
With your dead bodies.
Wheeler's footage made it out.
That Super 8 film he took in 76.
I processed it.
With my own hands.
That's why I know it's real.
Now. people say it was a fake. but I
know. I know it was real. Then let us go
down there.
Let us prove that it's real.
It'll prove there's nothing down there.
We're going to go right through every
chamber.
I'm betting we'll just come out the
other side. I think we'll be fine.
Look. we will share all of our findings.
Photos. videos. everything.
We just need to know which cave.
Look. if I tell you that. I will have
more blood on my hands.
More blood?
Mr. Harrifin. you know my mother is
missing.
Yes?
Did she come here?
Yes.
So she came here looking for her father
and you told her which cave? Look. she
was persistent.
She kept on and on and on. Couldn't get
rid of her.
Did you try pointing a gun at her?
Ethan!
Professor. we're going to go down there
with or without your help.
We have to.
If you try and find that cave without
me. it will be like looking for a needle
in a haystack in a field full of
haystacks.
Well. we just need to know which
haystack we're looking at.
That's all.
Look. we'll show all the findings to
you. The photos. the videos.
We'll give you everything you want.
Please. We've come a long way.
My mum went in there. If something has
happened to her. I at least need to try.
Yeah. and there's six of us this time.
Yeah.
The safety of numbers will help each
other.
Do you remember this?
This is my grandfather's journal.
This is all my mother got back.
Some sort of map.
The route that he took.
This is where we're going.
That first light.
We're going to keep going.
Very well.
But there's something you should see
first.
Now. you understand that this entire
cave system here is dangerous.
The descent alone is treacherous. There
are hundreds of caverns under there.
maybe thousands.
Most have never been explored. and very
few have been mapped.
play systems your whole life?
Yes. I have. But more particularly.
since I saw this footage. your
footage. and I saw it.
You see. I know that this footage is
real.
I processed this film.
It has not been faked or changed or
altered. This is what he saw.
Light screen.
You see that? That's a hot spring. The
whole system has changed because the
underneath has collapsed.
But the hot spring is still there
somewhere underneath.
And where there is a hot source of water
in a cave. there is probably an
ecosystem.
Now this is the entrance to the cave.
And here he's looking for miles.
Now we're getting quite close to it now.
Olivia. are you all right to continue?
Okay. the moment's come.
There! Oh. come on. That could be
anything. Rocks falling. camera shake.
anything. Yes.
Yes. Yes. that's what they all said.
But now let's look at this frame by
frame. shall we?
All right.
Holy shit. what is that? One single
frame of film. and for 50 years.
I've asked myself that very question.
What is that?
Where did it come from?
A theory. Look at that thing.
There is nothing like that on Earth. and
it made short work of your grandfather.
And have you read the police report?
Blood everywhere. all over the camera.
Extraordinary marks on the rocks.
I'm sorry. Olivia.
Why did he go back?
Because he wanted to find the proof.
He saw something in that first trip that
made him want to find the evidence.
Look. deep marks unlike anything I've
ever seen.
What animal could have done this?
And this.
Higher than any bear could reach.
You really think it's a creature?
Something unknown from another world. So
wait. are you saying that this is a
creature from another planet?
Because. I mean. that's a viral video if
we can get it. right?
Well. life could be spread by meteorites
from one part
of the universe or one part of the
galaxy to another.
Every part of Earth has been exposed to
meteorite activity.
In fact. there is one quite close to
that cave.
So let me get this straight.
You're saying an extraterrestrial being
landed on Earth and the first thing it
decides is to take residence in one of
these caves?
I know. A cave is the nearest thing we
have on Earth to space.
It is timeless.
There is no day. no night. You can't
actually be serious.
Look. I know it sounds absurd. Listen to
yourself.
Creatures. aliens. what's wrong with
you? I know it's extraordinary.
Extraordinary? It's just an old wives'
tale. Her mum's missing. You're rambling
on about aliens. Because I've seen it!
I have seen it. and it attacked me.
I was
a 12 -year -old boy.
I was playing in the woods. and I was
exploring. and I wanted to find where
meteor had hit.
I
heard
something in the cave. and it was an
animal voice. but it wasn't any animal
I'd ever heard.
It grasped my leg.
I have never felt such pain.
I don't know how I got myself free. but
I did. and I ran.
Four
operations.
Blood poisoning.
It nearly lost me twice.
The doctor said it could have been some
sort of wild dog.
Wild dog?
All right.
Well. you've seen what I've seen. and
you know what I know.
You still want to go down there?
I will tell you where it is.
On these conditions. one that you stick
together.
Two. that you do not seek the creature.
What you must do is find some tiny bit
of evidence. anything.
If you have that. we can send a
scientific expedition down there. If the
expedition could actually find what I
think is down there. you will have
a measure of real scientific immortality
because you will have helped answer one
of the greatest questions that has
always been around.
Okay.
Wow. Look at the formation.
This is the site of the impact crater.
Several hundred thousand years ago.
So. we going down or what?
Let's do it.
Yeah.
this is definitely it guys.
Okay. we need to pack down light. It's
going to be pretty cramped down there
we're going to feel everything we carry.
So. done what you don't need and fuel
up.
Hard hats on.
Torches. water.
Make sure you've got enough. It's going
to be hot down there.
Everything you're not bringing. stash it
in.
Think of Batman.
Hey. BitTiger Nation.
This is it. The moment of truth. The
infamous Geary Chase.
The home to the so -called Bonekeeper.
I'm going to be honest.
I don't believe in monsters.
But the people that we're missing.
something happened to them.
And we are going to find the truth. That
is a bitch hiker promise.
Hey. Ashley. you ready or what?
Cutie. cool.
Oh. and if I don't come back. delete my
browser history.
Just kidding.
The bitch hiker always comes back.
That's my brand.
I'm with you. okay?
Maybe step it away.
I feel like she's here.
Like she came here. you know?
And you're here for them both?
Seriously. guys?
Well. I can imagine it smells pretty bad
down in them caves about us
contributing towards it.
And as much as I love you guys. I don't
want to be tripping over a rock into a
puddle of you.
So I suggest you get out now.
Good.
Okay. this is it.
Ready? Yeah.
Ladies first?
Just kidding.
Good? So it's been on for a while.
Yeah.
It's definitely pretty stable.
Okay. keep going.
I think we should keep heading this way.
That's right.
Okay.
mind that.
Jump.
Okay. let's go.
How deep is this?
Not deep enough.
This is the first of many levels.
Great. Well. if you want to quit now's
the time. You can head back. warm up the
tents. maybe get some beans. some
sausages. and we'll see you on the other
in the morning.
How weird is this?
What is that?
Let me see.
Ravi. have you got the tools?
Yeah.
It's a pretty lightly organic deposit.
Probably from an organism of some kind.
I imagine.
Yeah. so this one contains phosphate.
chloride. definitely
sulfide. and nitrate.
It's pretty cool.
Want to grab a sample?
Definitely.
Sure. it's hydrophobic.
Meaning? Like it's acid or something.
right?
No. that's hydrochloric.
Hydrophobic. The literal translation is
fear of water.
Hydrophobic molecules are non -polar.
meaning the atoms that make the
do not produce a static electric field.
What made it then?
I'm not quite sure.
But hopefully once we've tested it with
these samples. we'll be able to tell
what the species is from.
Well. you have to keep doing those while
we're down there.
You're not going to be able to upload
them until we're out anyway. I'm going
collect all my assets. There we are.
And now I've just thought again. can I
just get like 30 seconds of silence?
No. actually. if they're here. catch us
up.
Unless you're scared and maybe you want
someone to stay with you.
I need to pee anyway.
It's too bad there's one stone.
When you guys are done with the science
lesson. let's keep going.
Come in.
I'll just be a sec.
Suit yourself.
What's the holdup?
There's a way through here. guys.
Ethan?
Nick. if that's you guys this isn't
funny.
Maybe we should stop for a minute.
Okay?
Figure out where we're going next.
Well. there's two chambers.
What do you want to do now?
We should split into two groups.
Harrison literally said stick together.
Well. according to this. it says the
chambers will meet up again further
so... Look. we are sticking together.
just in two groups. okay?
It's up to you. but unless we fully
explore both tunnels. we haven't fully
explored the whole cave system.
Yeah. exactly.
That's the whole point of coming. right?
Yeah.
All right. come on. guys. let's just
take a vote. yeah?
All in favour of splitting into two and
covering both?
Wait.
Ashley hasn't caught up with us yet.
Do you really think it's a good idea for
us to split into two groups without
her?
Yeah.
Yes.
Okay. well. why don't you go back. pick
whatever tunnel you fancy. and if you
see a little corner on the way. maybe
get cosy for a bit.
See you on the other side.
Great choice of words.
Cool. Let's do it.
Okay. I feel okay.
Ditto.
Keep safe. mate.
The composition could be dead animals or
something lovely
We should get a sample of that. Yeah.
No way.
No. I can't take a piece of someone's
head.
Give it to me.
Seriously?
That's great evidence.
Salt and vinegar all over it.
Well. yeah. It probably acts as a pretty
decent preservative. right?
Come on.
They're going to get way ahead of us.
Let's go.
Move.
Ashley! Ashley!
Ashley. are you there?
Ashley!
Claire?
that's funny
Does anyone get that feeling like
they're being watched?
It's probably just Nick.
He's a bit of a perv.
You'll want to talk.
It's a limestone structure.
Clay deposit.
It's pretty cool.
Oh my god. what is that?
Bradley. look.
Hey girls. come on.
Hey girls. you okay?
Those bones look human.
Yeah.
And fresh.
Look at that.
That is weird.
Just certainly.
I don't know. I thought I...
You
all right?
Yeah. yeah. I'm fine. I'm fine.
What the hell was that?
It's destabilising the structure.
No. Nadia. I don't think... Why not?
Nadia. be careful.
I'll get this closer.
Bradley. are you getting this?
Get it. record it. record it.
Oh. yeah.
Amazing.
Oh. my God.
It's the kind of new species I've...
I've never seen it before.
I've kept you close.
Leave the gear behind.
That's not rust.
And that wasn't torn by the rocks.
We should keep going.
Sounds like...
Okay.
if we can squeeze through then.
We can make it up. right?
Okay.
Let's go.
Breathe in.
Oh. my God. Oh. my God.
Oh. my God.
Oh. my God. Oh. my God. Oh. my God. Oh.
my God.
Oh. my God.
Oh.
my God.
Oh my God. What is that?
Guys.
we need to run.
It was a trophy of all of us. It was a
trophy.
We have to run.
Come on.
All the way up.
What is it?
What was that?
I don't know.
I think they're everywhere.
They're everywhere. They're everywhere.
You can see it.
They don't like the light.
Come on. wake up. Robbie. wake up.
Robbie. wake up. Quick. give me
light. Robbie. put them.
Get them. Get the lights on.
Quick. get them to put them.
The lights. get them.
Come on.
Thank you.
I couldn't do it.
I need to keep moving.
Which way?
We're lost. Ethan.
There's no way we can follow the map
now.
I don't think we can be anywhere.
There's a ramp.
Look.
There's a slope.
Let's try this way.
Come on. What about Nadia?
And Nick?
We have to assume that...
Wait.
wait. wait.
Can you hear that?
It's just the wind roughing through the
cave.
No. no. no.
Listen.
Ethan. We're going back for him.
Ethan.
We need to stick together.
Let's get Ravi out.
We'll come back.
Let's go.
That's it.
They're not following.
Not even the moonlight.
I'll be back.
Don't go far.
I got you. I got you.
I still my leg. I still my leg.
Lydia? Annabel?
Ethan? This way.
Ethan?
Over here.
Please get him in the tent. There's a
first aid kit as well.
We lost signal.
About a mile back.
I'm going to go call Phil.
Okay?
I'll come with you.
I'll be faster on my own. Stay here.
I'll be back.
Be careful.
All of us.
Do what?
I can't believe we made it out.
We're not safe yet.
This is all my fault.
It's not what we think.
It's older than people.
No. you're here first.
He's burning up.
The fever. He's probably got an
infection.
Inside you.
Here comes you.
You heard me. Ravi.
I knew.
Ravi.
Ravi. you heard me. You saw.
I think you need to rest a bit.
I need to get some sleep.
Harrison.
Professor. Listen. you were right. You
were right about everything and
something. Whoa. whoa. whoa. Slow down.
boy.
Stop. Breathe.
What happened?
Are you fucked up. man? It's a fucking
nightmare down there. There's people
fucking parts of people everywhere.
It's not a cave. it's a fucking nest.
It's a fucking nest. man!
Ethan! Say something. Harrison. please.
Please. I don't know how long we've got.
Take a breath.
Olivia.
is she safe?
Yeah. Olivia's safe.
She's safe. She's with Annabelle and
Ravi by the tent.
But. um. Ravi's hurt. He's hurt real
bad. There's blood everywhere.
Did you?
I saw something. It was like nothing
I've ever seen. It was merged with parts
Nick and... I don't know what I saw.
okay. but... Ashley's missing.
Nadia's missing.
I think they're dead.
Do you have proof?
I'm sending more than that.
Brace yourself.
Right.
Send me everything you've got.
The police will need evidence. You have
my email.
Please. be quick. It's a bloody mess.
I'm not sure how long we got left.
Well done.
In that weird wall.
She never took that necklace off.
She can't.
I need to go back in. Annabelle.
I need to see if that was her necklace.
I need to know.
Come on. come on.
Morrie? Harrington here.
You wanted proof?
I've got you proof.
Somebody's out there.
I heard something.
I heard it too.
Did you hear that?
I suggest you get your men over there.
Armed.
Ethan?
Ethan. is that you?
Burn!
There's a woman inside.
I don't give a damn who's in there.
We're blowing that case. Get your hands
Primary site secure.
Evidence of casualties.
Secondary search underway.
Mama. it's been a lifesaver at times.
We're going to blow the cave in three
minutes. I need everyone out. Let's go!
It's okay.
You're going to be okay.
Where am I?
You've been in a coma for six months.
The good news is. not only are you going
to make a full recovery.
you're a baby too.
You are.
Let's have a quick look. shall we?
No.
no. no.
Thank you.
Yes. Home Secretary.
Six went in.
One was saved.
Yes. I know. There is a point I wish to
make. Home Secretary.
Blowing the entrance of the cave does
not end the matter.
There could be passageway to other
caves.
And we do not know how many of these
creatures are. or indeed. what is their
nature.
May I suggest we actually send an
expedition from there. properly armed.
ascertain the nature of the threat.
For I believe it could be an existential
threat.
That poor girl.
Now. that's not something we're going to
forget about in a hurry.
Well. you've just got to forget about
it.
That's what that bonus money's for.
Not a word outside this building.
Got it?
Take care. man.
You too.
Come on. Matthew. let's get it together.